Now, let's calculate a metric of the total risk inherent to the portfolio.
下面计算投资组合总风险指标
We'll measure risk with volatility or more specifically with the variance,
我们将用波动率衡量风险
the square of the volatility.
也就是方差 即波动率的平方
Let's review the formula for the variance of one asset.
我们回顾下一个资产的方差公式
This is a slightly different formula for variance than we've seen before,
与我们之前见过的方差公式不太一样
but it's similar in spirit.
但本质上是一样的
Instead of just summing the squared difference between
之前是计算每个观察量与均值之差的平方和
each observation and the mean and dividing by n,
然后除以 n
we multiply the squared difference by
现在我们用观察量与均值之差的平方
the probability of that value occurring and sum those.
乘以发生观察量发生的概率 然后求和
The formula will be the same as dividing by n,
之前的公式除以 n 后是一样的
if the probability of each scenario occurring is the same.
前提是每种情形的发生概率是一样的
So, now let's calculate the variance of the portfolio.
下面计算投资组合的方差
This takes just a few simple steps,
只需简单的几个步骤
but for now we will skip ahead to the answer.
我们先直接看最终公式
You'll find the full derivation given as text on this page.
本页面的文字部分会讲解完整的推导过程
We find that the portfolio variance equals the
我们发现投资组合方差等于
squared of weights times each asset's variance,
权重平方乘以每个资产的方差
plus a term that includes the covariance of the assets multiplied by each weight.
再加上一项 这项等于资产的协方差乘以每个权重
Remember that the covariance is a measure of
协方差是指
the joint variability of two random variables.
两个随机变量的联合变化性
When stock A is above its average,
如果股票 A 高于平均值
if stock B is also above its average,
并且 B 也高于平均值
they are varying together or covarying,
那么它们共同变化或共变
so they have a positive covariance.
所以协方差为正向
This covariance term turns out to be very important.
这个协方差项很重要
It basically underlies the benefit of diversification.
它代表了分散投资的好处
Remember that the covariance is just the correlation
协方差等于
between the two variables times each of their standard deviations.
两个变量的相关性乘以各自的标准差
We know that the correlation coefficient takes values between minus one and one,
我们知道相关系数的值在 -1 到 1 之间
where minus one means the variables are perfectly anti-correlated,
-1 表示两个变量完全反相关
and one means that they are perfectly correlated.
1 表示完全相关
Both correlation and covariance are measures of how much two variables vary together.
相关性和协方差都衡量的是两个变量相互变化的关系
With this knowledge, we can rewrite the portfolio variance in terms of the correlation.
知道这些知识后 我们可以用相关性表示投资组合方差
Let's see what happens to the variance of
如果 A 和 B 的相关性是 1
our two-asset portfolio when the correlation between stock A and stock B is one.
那么投资组合的方差会变成什么？
In that case, the expression to the right of the equal sign is a perfect square,
等号右边的表达式变成一个完美的平方
and the portfolio standard deviation is
投资组合标准差等于
just a weighted average of the standard deviations of the individual stocks.
单个股票标准差的加权平均值
In all other cases,
在所有其他情形下
the correlation coefficient is less than one.
相关系数都小于 1
So the portfolio standard deviation is less than
所以投资组合标准差小于
the weighted average of the individual standard deviations.
单个标准差的加权平均值
How about when the correlation between stock A and B is minus one?
如果 A 和 B 的相关性是 -1 呢？
In that case, the portfolio variance reduces to
在这种情形下 投资组合方差变成
the weighted difference between the two standard deviations squared
两个标准差加权差分值的平方
and the portfolio standard deviation becomes
投资组合标准差变成
the absolute weighted difference between the individual standard deviations.
单个标准差的绝对加权差分值
In the case when the correlation is minus one,
如果相关性是 -1
we can get a perfectly hedged portfolio by solving this equation.
通过求解这个方程 我们可以得出完全对冲的投资组合
If we plug in the relation that the weights x_A and x_B sum to one,
代入方程 x_A + x_B = 1
we get that x_A equals Sigma B divided by Sigma A plus Sigma B.
得出 x_A = σ_B/(σ_A+σ_B)
These weights drive the portfolio variance to zero.
这些权重使投资组合方差变成 0
However, in reality, since every asset is affected by systematic risk,
但是 在现实中 因为所有资产都受到系统性风险的影响
the correlation between two assets will never reach minus one.
所以两个资产的相关性不可能达到 -1